<courses>
<course>
<name>Business Startup</name>
<id>1</id>
<image>http://api.bibro.ml/academy/images/course_img_startup.jpg</image>
<count>4</count>
<chapter>
	<name>The Entrepreneur</name>
	<desc>The decision to start your own company is nt an easy one to make. It can be a rewarding and often challengig undertaking. If you are considering starting a new venture, you need to know the risks you may be taking, why some startups fail, the financial and time commitments involved, and the factors that help create successful business.</desc>
	<count>5</count>	
		<slide>
		<name>What is the first step if you have a great business idea?</name>
		<body>Whatever your motivation, the first step is to reflect upon your own personality and the resources you have available.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What does it take to be a successful entrepreneur?</name>
		<body>A desire for success, being open to risk-taking and leadership skills are important, but there are other personality traits necessary to become a successful entrepreneur. Look over this cheklist to see if you have got what it takes:
- Self confidence;
- Persistence and resilience (the ability to keep going and - recover after setback);
- An ability to identify needs and solve problems;
- Lots of energy.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What pesonality trait should an entrepreneur possess?</name>
		<body>It takes all kinds of people to make the worls go round. There are those who like to follow and those who like to lead. A business owner needs to have an instinct for leadership - among other skills.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What are the disadvantages of owning your own business?</name>
		<body>There are many disadvantages to business ownership.
As well as the risk of failure and financial loss, reduced leisure time and reduced pay during difficult times, there are also long hours during the start-up phase and challenging times; the lack of a company pension or health benefits; and having to adhere to strict record keeping, legal requirements and tax reporting.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is good to have when starting a business?</name>
		<body>If you are still deciding if you are ready to take on the challenge of business ownership, the next step is to take stock of what resources and suppogrt may currently be available to you to help with your startup efforts.</body>
		</slide>
</chapter>
<chapter>
	<name>Ideas and Goals</name>
	<desc>The decision to start your own company is not an easy one to make. It can be a rewarding and often challenging undertaking. If you are considering starting a new venture, you need to know the risks you may be taking, why some startups fail, the financial and time commitments involved, and the factors that help create successful business.</desc>
	<count>8</count>
		<slide>
		<name>What does entrepreneurship involve?</name>
		<body>Does yourBusiness idea fulfill a need in the marketplace that no other company is offering? Does your concept improve upon an existing product or service? Does your vision change the marketplace altogether?</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What inspires business creativity?</name>
		<body>Some ideas are so simple you have  to wonder why nobody thought of them before. Other ideas are so earth-shattering that you wonder how they ever came to exist.
- Listen intently to your "inner voice",
also known as your intuition;
- Follow your passion;
- Collaborate with others;
- Closely examine existing products and services;
- Research the industry that interests you;
- Be open to new ideas and random thoughts when you are working on other things.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>Why do people hesitate to develop their business idea?</name>
		<body>If you are hesitate about taking the next step, ask yourself why? Usually, fear is what holds people back from fulfilling their dreams. Try to to really get in touch with your fear. When you identify and name it, you can take steps to confront it.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What can make a product or seervice command a high price?</name>
		<body>Markets are, quite simply, comprised of buyers and sellers. The selling price of a product or service is established by the relationship created by the forces of supply (how much exists) and demand (how much people want it).</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is the first priority when setting up a business?</name>
		<body>No matter how big or small your business, you will have to set aside some time and resources to develop your business idea before you launch it.
The planning and research that you do now will help ensure that your idea is practical, realistic and achievable.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is the most important question to ask yourself when setting goals for your business?</name>
		<body>In order to set your financial goals, you will have to do some basic research to determine your realistic financial reward, based on your proposed business activity and level of time commitment. In addition to talking to people who are already in the field that interests you, you could search online for average sales numbers for similar business and contact your local trade association to inquire about statistics on their member's business activity.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What personal sacrifices does setting up your own business involve?</name>
		<body>One of the most appealing parts of starting your own company is being your own boss. Working for yourself offers lifestyle flexibility but can also require much more of a time commitment, depending on the nature and intensity of your business.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is a key component to philantrophy?</name>
		<body>Some business people start their wn companies because, in addition to looking for financial rewards, they have a stroong desire to make the world a better place. That is excatly what entrepreneur Bake Mycoskie had in mind when he founded TOMS Shoes - for each pair of shoes his company sell, it donates a pair to an impoverished child in a developing country.</body>
		</slide>
</chapter>
<chapter>
	<name>Your Business Plan</name>
	<desc>The decision to start your own company is not an easy one to make. It can be a rewarding and often challenging undertaking. If you are considering starting a new venture, you need to know the risks you may be taking, why some startups fail, the financial and time commitments involved, and the factors that help create successful business.</desc>
	<count>7</count>
		<slide>
		<name>What must follow your business idea and goals?</name>
		<body>A business plan is a formal document that can be presented to investors, bankers and potential business partners. It can be as simple or as detailed as your venture requires, as long as it helps you focus on how to achieve your goals.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What should your business plan be based on?</name>
		<body>The most important step in preparing to draft your business plan will be the research. There are two important areas for which you will need to gather data: your marketing plan and your financial plan.
You may have a trusted friend, family member or colleague who has the expertise to help you write your business plan. Don't be afraid to ask for help and remember: research, research, research. To homework you do now will pay off later.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What must a business plan explain?</name>
		<body>Now, jump in and start writing your business plan. Business writing should always be clear and concise, Keep in mind that business people are busy and will want to be able to skim your document quickly to find the information they are looking for.
- The existing ooportunity in the marketplace and who your customer is;
- The size of the potential market for this product or service;
- A description of your product or service and what makes it unique or better than other products currently for sale;
- Your business team and how your company will be organised;
- Your financial plan;
- Your milestones (how long it will take you to break even on your initial investment, etc.)</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>How should a business plan be presented?</name>
		<body>Your plan should be formatted in a visually pleasing yet simple manner. Stick to a minimum of two fonts and make sure the document is neatly printed and bound. This will be the fiirst opportunity to show potential investors that you are organised and proffesional.
Ehat it needs
A business plan will include the following elements to effectively present your concepts:
Table of contents: provides the reader with an outline of what they can expect within the plan.
Executive summary: explains the overall idea of your business plan and provides key points.
Company overview: outlines the profile of your organisation and describes your company's vision, mision, values and products or services.
Company description: provides details about your business and indentifies its competitive advantage in the marketplace.
Company strategy: details the current state of the marketplace and how you will promote your product or service to compete.
Financial plan: provides a breakdown of the start-up costs required, the current state of the company's financial and forecast of income and expenses.
Action plan: Is a step-by-step plan for implementing your startup and strategy moving forward.
Appedices: may include supporting documents such as industry studies, blueprints, equipment lists, leases, legal documents, letters of recommendation.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>Who will be interested in your business plan?</name>
		<body>Once you have drafted a professional-looking, well-researched and realistic business plan, you can use that plan to attract interest for whether purpose you require.
Think about who you will need to approach to help you turn your idea into reality.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>How can you expand your business network?</name>
		<body>Cold-calling is the practice of directly calling or emailing a prospective business contact in the absence of an introduction from a mutual colleague.
When you don't have any of your own contacts who can help or collaborate, you will need to start cold-calling in order to set up meetings. Cold-calling is one of the most difficult business skills to master, but there are some tried and true tips to help you excel at it. Read on to find out how:
- Ensure that the person you are contacting will actually be interested in your business idea;
- Most people have a fear of rejection, but there is generally another issue underlying it. Are you afraid of appearing foolish or being humiliated? Determine the underlying fear so that you can take steps to overcome it.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What should you do when giving a business presentation?</name>
		<body>This may be your first opportunity to share your business idea, and it can be a bit daunting.
Here are a few presentation tips to help you make the best impression you can:
- Make sure that you have your presentation down pat. Be calm and confident;
- Avoid talking about yourself. Instead, present how your idea can benefit your audience;
- Avoid using acronyms and be sure to explain any echnical industry-specific terms that come up.</body>
		</slide>
</chapter>
<chapter>
	<name>Team and Structure</name>
	<desc>The decision to start your own company is not an easy one to make. It can be a rewarding and often challenging undertaking. If you are considering starting a new venture, you need to know the risks you may be taking, why some startups fail, the financial and time commitments involved, and the factors that help create successful business.</desc>
	<count>8</count>
		<slide>
		<name>What must you have for your business to succeed?</name>
		<body>By now you are confident and clear about your vision for your business. You should be just as clear about the kind of people you want on your team.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What should guide you before you hire someone?</name>
		<body>You can interview the most talented, experienced people, and they might be eager to join your team. A brilliant resume and the right credentials is all it really takes, right? Not so fast. When choosing team members, it is best to listen to your instincts.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What does the so-called "chain of command" ensure?</name>
		<body>Whatever your organizational structure, everyone on your team will need to clearly understand who they directly report to.
As the founder of the company, you will likely be the leader of your entire team. However, occasionally, the founder will step back to put a general manager in control of the day-to-day business operations, while he or she takes care of the more top-level decision making.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is important to follow when starting a company?</name>
		<body>Whether you need to hire one part-time assistant or hundreds of full-time staff for your new venture, you will need to follow good hiring practices in order to recruit the best candidates and also to fulfil your legal and ethical obligations.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What type of company lets the owner have all the profits?</name>
		<body>Advantages of sole ownership:
- Simple and inexpensive to register;
- Few legal restrictions;
- You are the sole decision maker;
- All profits will go to you;
- Sole ownership is the least complicated company structure.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is a benefit of setting up a partnership?</name>
		<body>Partnerships make sense for certain entrepreneurs who don't wish to take on the business risks all by themselves and who don't want to inccorporate.
Other advantages:
- Relatively simple to register;
- Costs of starting the business are shared by the partners;
- Responsibilities are shared, as well as profits and assets.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is an advantage of structuring your company as a corporation?</name>
		<body>Corporations (also known as limited liability or unlimited companies) are more complicated to set up and register but are usually the right choice for entrepreneurs who have legal and tax requirements.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What are some diasadvantages of the cooperative business structure?</name>
		<body>In some jurisdictions, an additional type of business is available: a cooperative (also known as co-op). This sort of business iiis owned and controlled by its members in a democratic way.</body>
		</slide>
</chapter>
</course>
<course>
<name>Successful Negotiating</name>
<id>2</id>
<image>http://api.bibro.ml/academy/images/course_img_negotiation.jpg</image>
	<count>4</count>
	<chapter>
		<name>Prepare and Listen</name>
		<desc>Negotiation is part of our everyday life. Whether you are negotiating in a job or a business situtation or with family or friends it is a good skill to have. In this course you find out which skills you need to have to be a successful negotiatoor.</desc>
		<count>9</count>	
			<slide>
			<name>What is the goal of any nogotiation?</name>
			<body>Negotiating is a way of getting what you want by putting your point across in the most convincing way. But what is it that you really want? Here are some tools to find out:
- Make a list of what you want and why you want it;
- Divide the list into must haves and what you are willing to flexible on;
- Define your bottom line of what you are willing to be settle for;
- Identify how the outcome of this negotiation will affect others.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do with your goals?</name>
			<body>Be clear about what you hope to gain. If you don't know where you are going, it is hard to get there. When there is more han one goal to gain, you need to set your priorities. Make concessions on matters of less importance to secure more important items.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Why should you research your counterpart for negotiation?</name>
			<body>If you have a job or are negotiating for a job contract, try to do some research on the person and the copany you are negotiating with. Perhaps you and your interviewer share a similar past experience. When you show that you know a fact or two about the other person, you usually score points with the interviewer and it serves as an ice-breaker.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How prepared should you be for a negotiating?</name>
			<body>Good preparation will allow you to know exactly what your position is and what your goals are. You will understand the other party's priorities, concerns and needs and thereby be able to work out a solution that works out for everyone. The time spent in preparing will probably be the best time you spend in the process.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is a negoatiating no-no?</name>
			<body>Give undivided attention and do not interrupt the counterpart. Look him in the eyes when he is talking to you. Do not interrupt when the other party is speaking. You are not only being tude, you might also be miss information that could be of great importance.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is a closed question?</name>
			<body>Questions may be open-ended and expansive or closed-ended and restrictive.
Open-ended questions do not lead the other party any specific direction. Generally speaking, they reveal much more about the counterpart's feelings and needs than restrictive questions do.
Your questions should have tw goals:
1. To get more and specific information;
2. To uncover the other party's needs.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is as important as what someone is saying</name>
			<body>No doubt verbal cues are important; but it is equally important to understand non-verbal cues. A negotiator doesn't normally put his entire message into words. His verbal message may express honesty and commitment, while his gestures, facial expressionss and voice might say something completely different.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How should you begin a professional negotiation?</name>
			<body>Give your counterpart the chance to speak first and tell you what he/she wants to communicate. You will be surprised how much you can learn by just letting them talk.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is important to know before any negotiation?</name>
			<body>Make it your top priority to understand your counterpart's thinking and position. Here are some tools:
- Check the Internet. LinkedIn can give you a good overview of someone's professional past as well as interests;
- Brainstorm a list of their possible interests. It can help you identify your assets and how to utilise them at the negotiation table to get what you want;
- Findout what the biggest benefits you bring to the table are for the person you are negotiating with;
- Role-play the other side. Put the knowledge you know have to work. This acctivity step will ensure you know your counterpart's standpoint.</body>
			</slide>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<name>Goals, Limits, Impasses</name>
		<desc>Negotiation is part of our everyday life. Whether you are negotiating in a job or a business situtation or with family or friends it is a good skill to have. In this course you find out which skills you need to have to be a successful negotiatoor.</desc>
		<count>7</count>
			<slide>
			<name>How can we best communicate our goals to others?</name>
			<body>To void ambiguity, quantify your goals as muuch as possible. If you are selling your car, saying "I want as much as money for it as I can get it", is not a good negotiation statement. Set specific measurable results to the goal.
You should document your goals. It allows you to see them in a concrete format which makes them seem real.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Why is it good to tell another person about your goal?</name>
			<body>Making your friends, family or co-workers partof your goal-setting process can be very useful i helping you reach your objective. Your goals will impact those arround you so it is important to let them know what you are up to. Also, telling another person about your goal makes it real and puts a healthy pressure on you to keep working toward your objective.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Why is it important to create a list of alternatives?</name>
			<body>It is important to strike a balance between goals that are too low and those that are too high. If your goals are too low then you have missed an opportunity to do better. If they are too high, you risk feeling frustrated as they may be unattainable. Try to set realistic goals.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is the goal of replacing a negotiator?</name>
			<body>Sometimes you find yourself at an impasse because one or more of the negotiator just doesn't want to look at the situation from different angle. This generally happens when the negotiations have been dragged on for a long time. If you replace the negotiator, you may find that the negotiations take a step back as the new negotiator first has to develop a relationship with the other side of the tavle. But, this might be just what is needed to move the discussions forward.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is the best thing to do when you cannot reach an agreement?</name>
			<body>In general, an impasse is a result of the negotiating parties not having the authority needed to suggest alternatives. If so, kick up the problem to higher powers. They do have the power to come up with alternatives and can swifty bring the whole discussion back on track.
If you can change the setting, both sides will feel like they are starting the negotiation all over again. This fresh outlook might just be what you need to break the impasses and renegotiate the entire issue from stratch.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>When should you ask for a pause?</name>
			<body>When you feel pressurised or under stress you can ask for a pause. You might prevennt yourself from saying things you may later regret. It also provides a moment of reflection. This gives you the time to think about your reactions so that you don't close the dealtoo quickly and regret about it later. How to initiate a pause?
- If the negotiation gets complicated and you do not want to get firther into the matter, ask for a night to think the nagotiation iover. Most people will respect your request to "sleep on it";
Excuse yourself to go ti the restroom. Of course this will never be a proble;
- I a business situation you can always say that you have to run it by your partner and get back to you the next morning;
- Ask for a drink break. This will give you time to thik over the matter;
- Ask for a clarification on some topic that has already been covered.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do whenan agreement does not meet your len-term goals?</name>
			<body>Take some extra time to find out the counterpart's motivations.
Does this agreement reach the goals and the limits you set for this particular negotiation?
YES - Good news! You are well on the way of reaching a win-win negotiation.
NO - Bad news! Take a break to figure out a way the other party can meet your expectations or think about a compromise that is acceptable for you.</body>
			</slide>			
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<name>Men VS. Women</name>
		<desc>Negotiation is part of our everyday life. Whether you are negotiating in a job or a business situtation or with family or friends it is a good skill to have. In this course you find out which skills you need to have to be a successful negotiatoor.</desc>
		<count>7</count>
			<slide>
			<name>What do women generally do in negotiations?</name>
			<body>Let's take a closer look at the behaviour women display while negotiating:
- Seek to build a relationship;
- Care for other people;
- Do not like to hurt the connection that is built;
Tend to avoid conflicts;
- Are more cooperative;
- Are resistant to begin a negotiation.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How do men behave in a negotiation situation?</name>
			<body>Now take a look at the behaviour of men sitting at the negotiation table:
- Prefer to act dominant;
- Tend to be more aggressive;
- Seek to make a deal;
- Care less about the counterpart's feelings;
- Seek conflicts;
- Seek win-lose negotiation in their favor;
- Are straightforward.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Which sex is generally more positive aheadof a negotiation?</name>
			<body>Because of our gender difference, you have to plan different negotiation strategies. In general, women try to buld up relationship, are more compassionate and take a more non-aggresive stance. Men on the other hand, seek what they want to get out of the negotiation, not so worried abut what will haappen after the deal is done.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How can you become more effective at negotiating?</name>
			<body>Keep it short and be direct. In general, women create relationships by talking to each other about almost anything and going into every detail. That is ow they becoe friends. Men talk to exchange information. In a negotiation, be aware no to go into every detail and be direct. Make sure that the counterpart pays attention to your message and does not lose concentration.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do when you feel you are getting very emotional?</name>
			<body>Do not show too many emotions. They get in the way of negotiations. It distracts too much which is not empowering your position. When you notice hat you are about to show emotions, take a break and leave the room for a moment. Take a deep breath, pull yourself together and do not return until you feel you have got your act together again.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What isn't it smart for men to be so "closed" in front of women?</name>
			<body>Most men do not usually share their thoughts. If you are highly secretive and silent bot your motivations and thoughts, a women might think you have shut down; and will become frustrated and less willing to come to an agreement. Open up a bit.
Studies show that a woman's bigest frustration with a man is his failure to pen up. Share something about your background and your family.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do when giving a business How can women have more impact when negotiating?</name>
			<body>Women have to empower their message by skipping words or phrases that weaken their message. Easier said than done since women in eneral, tend to use more words. Here are a couple of tools for women to practice on:
- Do not use weak words like "Maybe", "sort of", "I probably might" and "kind of". These words display uncertainty and weaken the message;
- Do not use questionning tones. Because of thehigh intonation at the end of the question, the speaker sounds like she is unsure and is desperate need for confirmation;
- Do not try to fill in the silence with affirmative words like "mm ... mm", "yes ... yes ..." or "absolutely". You don't have to fill every second with sound.</body>
			</slide>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<name>Crossing Borders</name>
		<desc>Negotiation is part of our everyday life. Whether you are negotiating in a job or a business situtation or with family or friends it is a good skill to have. In this course you find out which skills you need to have to be a successful negotiator.</desc>
		<count>5</count>
			<slide>
			<name>How much should you research the culture of the other patrty?</name>
			<body>Successful international negotiators never engage without careful preparation. It is imperative to gather as much information as you can about a culture before you start a negotiation. Do so by readng books and travel guides from the country, or countries you are dealing with
Search and get the right person if you are thinking of doing business in another country. Whether you want a distriibutor or a representative of your company, it always helps if you have a person who knows the local culture, market and language of that place.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do when there is a conflict?</name>
			<body>Be patient and do not respond to any disagreement or conflict. If a conflict does occur, ask for a break and leave the table for a few minutes. Showing irritation is not only considered inappropriate in some cultures, but may also affect the outcome of the negotiation.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What How important is it to know your counterpart's long-term goals?</name>
			<body>It might surprise you to know that i some culters, business is a long-term commitment. People are not just doing business with you, the are actuall building a lifelong business relaionship with you. This kind of mindest actually decides the amount of time and effort they are willing to put in during negatiotians.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do after typing an important e-mail?</name>
			<body>Whether Take the time required to review what you have written. This allows you to look again at your pharing, make revisions and ensure there are no spellingor grammar mistakes. It doesn't gurt to even review what you have written the following day before you send it. You might be surprised by what you find today that you could not see yesterdsy.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What subject should you avoid while negotiating with different culters?</name>
			<body>Obviously, you should steer clear from sensitive opics like politis, rave and religion while negotiating.
Howeer, in some situations, thins might get personal and you can be asked about your marriage, family or even age.</body>
			</slide>			
	</chapter>
</course>
<course>
<name>The Tipping Point</name>
<id>3</id>
<image>http://api.bibro.ml/academy/images/course_img_tipping.jpg</image>
	<count>4</count>
	<chapter>
		<name>Why things tip?</name>
		<desc>This course expains how some things become widely popular, while others don&#39;t. This course explores the core concepts of The Tipping Point and factors that make ceratain ideas or behaviours become trends.</desc>
		<count>10</count>	
			<slide>
			<name>What do you call it when something suddenly starts to grow in popularity?</name>
			<body>When a product or behaviour starts to become popular, it is called a &#34;trend&#34;. A word that means almost the same thing is &#34;fad&#34;. However, the main difference is that a trend lasts longer.
The continuing popularity of mobile phoes is a trend. The brief popularity of orange&#x2013;coloured shirts is a fad.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is the &#34;tipping point&#34;?</name>
			<body>Trends usually start slowly.
At first,the number of people who follow a trend increases only gradually. At a certain point, though, enough people join the trend that everyone else starts to notice. At that point, the trend suddenly takes off and becomes very popular. That's the tipping point.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Where did the idea of a &#34;tipping point&#34; come from?</name>
			<body>The idea of tipping point comes from scales that are used for weighing.
If weights are gradually added to one side of the scale, nothing happens until the weights become as heavy as the item on the other side. At that point, as soon as you add just a little more weight, the scales suddently tip.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Where How are a flu virus and a trend similar?</name>
			<body>People spread the flu by being around each other. Trens start when people copy each other. One person coughing can quick;y spread the flu to others, and one person can spread a trend, if people copy him
It&#39;s hard to tel where a flu originated, it&#39;s also hard to tell where a trend came from.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Where How can a trend impact the financial success of a company?</name>
			<body>When a product or service suddenly becomes very popular, it can improvethe financial health of a company. The increased demand will result in more sales.
If, hwever, you are a competitor company and another brand becomes more popular, then your sales can decrease.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Besides our friends and family, wat also has a powerful influence on our behaviour?</name>
			<body>The environment around us includes everything, from the streets we live on, the buildings we work in, our transportationsystems, etc.
If this environment is orderly and pleasant, people are more likely to behave well. However, if it&#39;s poorly kept and untidy, thhey will probablyact badly.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>A hula hoop is a large plastic ring that children swing around their hips. How long did it take to sell the first 25 million hula hoops?</name>
			<body>Trends are like epidemics. They can spread quickly. Hula hoops were a trend &#x2013; or a fad &#x2013; that spread very quickly.
Something can become a trend in a matter of months or even weeks, just like a school might have no sick students on Monday and a hundred sick students by Friday.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What happens to a trend&#39;s rate of growth after it reaches a tipping point?</name>
			<body>Change doesn&#39;t always happen at a steady pace. It can take time to build up, or happen in burst rapidly. Sometimes, things grow or evolve slowly, bit by bit, over time.
But, then, quite suddenly, they reach a tipping point and everything escalates rapidly.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is the name of the mathematical growth pattern: 1, 2, 4, 8, 16, 32, ...?</name>
			<body>Some things spread faster and fster as they grow. When the flu spreads it starts with 1 person. That 1 person gives it to 2 people, who give it to 4 people, who give it to 8 people etc. The numver of people doubles every step. This called geometric progression, and it also applies trends.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Why were people initially reluctant to buy fax machines?</name>
			<body>Fax machines are used to send copies of documents. When fax machines were first invented, it didn't make sense to buy one because only a few other peole owned them. How would you use your fax machine, if you did&#39;t know anyone else who had one?</body>
			</slide>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<name>Big effects from small changes</name>
		<desc>This course expains how some things become widely popular, while others don&#39;t. This course explores the core concepts of The Tipping Point and factors that make ceratain ideas or behaviours become trends.</desc>
		<count>6</count>	
			<slide>
			<name>What percentage of car accidents are caused by just 20% of drivers?</name>
			<body>On average, people who have car accidents don&#39;t have just one car accident; they have many. In fact, 80% of all car accidents are caused by just 20% of drivers.
A small number of people can affect a large number of people. This is called the 80&#x2044;20 principle.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Where does the 80&#x2044;20 principle apply?</name>
			<body>The 80&#x2044;20 principle can apply to many ifferent businesses or environments.
For example, 20% of all criminals are responsible for 80% of all crime. In the USA, 20% of hospital patients use a staggering 80% of all health resources.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Who was the man known as &#34;Patients Zero&#34;?</name>
			<body>In the early 1980s, a flight attendant now known as &#34;Patient Zero&#34; gave a virus known as HIV to at least 40 people in various cities. Those people then spread HIV to others.
One person can have a big on a community.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Why did HIV kill more people in the 1980s than in previous decades?</name>
			<body>Virus such as HIV change continuosly. Sometimes they become more deadly or more contagious. It does not have to be a big change for it to alter the impact.
A small change in a product can cause it to become more &#34;contagious&#34;, and helps it reach its tipping point.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What kinds of changes can turn an ordinary product into a wildly successful one?</name>
			<body>If a product isn&#39;t selling well, try making a few small changes to either the product or its advertising. This can make a uge difference.
Winston&#39;s winner slogan
In 1954, the Winston cigarette company created the sloga: &#34;Winston tasets good like a cigarette should.&#34; Therhyming phrase caught on and, in just a few months, Winston movved from the sicth most popular cigarette to te second most popular. In a few more years, it became the most brand. Winston had&#39;t even changed their product. All they did was make a small change to how it  was advertised.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>In the USA, why do fewer people get sick suring the month of November?</name>
			<body>In the summer, when the weather is nice, people spend more time visiting with one another. In the winter, when it&#39;s cold, they spent more time by themselves indoors. As a result, diseases don&#39;t spread as much in the winter.
Something as simple as a change in temperature can have a big impact.</body>
			</slide>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<name>The people who make it happen</name>
		<desc>This course expains how some things become widely popular, while others don&#39;t. This course explores the core concepts of The Tipping Point and factors that make ceratain ideas or behaviours become trends.</desc>
		<count>10</count>	
			<slide>
			<name>How many people does it take to impact a large group?</name>
			<body>On a plane everyone breathes the same air. If just one passenger has a flu, they can potentially give it to many other passengers during the flight.
In a school, if a popular student starts wearing a certain kind of shoes, many other students are likely to start copying them.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is the term for someone who loves to learn about new things and share information with others?</name>
			<body>Some people are always the first to know abput something. They enjoy collecting new information and sharing it with others, They are called &#34;Mavens&#34;.
Mavens help people filter the large amount of information that exists in our digital age. They are the first step in making something into a trend.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What do you call someone who convinces others to do something?</name>
			<body>A salesperson is someone who convices you to try something.
Thay are&#39;t always actual salespeople. However, the way they encourage you to try new things earns them the name. When a friend tells you about a new barnd of coffee and convinces you to try it, they are acting as a salesperson.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>When you are dealing with people face&#x2013;to&#x2013;face, what can you use to help influence them?</name>
			<body>Your body language is just as important as your words when you&#39;re trying to convince someone of something. If your body language is positive as you talk to someone, the other person will start to feel positive.
People who are good at convincing others usually have expressive body language.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How Ehat is the best way to convince someone of something?</name>
			<body>If you are trying to convince someone of something, you might have more success if you meet with them in person rather than talking over the telephone.
On the telephone, you can&#39;t connvey emotion through body language. This makes it harder for you to convince the person you are talking to.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What must happen for atrend to jump from one group to another?</name>
			<body>Different groups like different things. A trend that is populat in one group may need to be re&#x2013;packaged or presented differently before another group will join it.
An investment may be popular with bankers if it&#39;s low risk, but with students it may need to be presented as environmentally&#x2013;friendly.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is it called when you hear about a new product from a friend?</name>
			<body>You can discover new products from advertisements. But you can also learn about them from friends. This is called word of mouth.
Word of mouth often happens through social media channels. Trends are often the ruslt. People pay less attention to TV ads these days, they listen to others instead.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What do you call someone who knows a large number of diverse people?</name>
			<body>Connectors know a lot of people in different and diverse groups.
They link person to another and various groups to other groups. They help trends &#34;jump&#34; from one group to another. People with social jobs are more likely to be connectors, others are connectors because of their personality.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is the maximum number of people in an effective group?</name>
			<body>The maximun size for any effective group is 150 people.
Any more than 150 in a single group makes it difficult to keep track of everyone and to get people to agree.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>When do most people decide to join a trend?</name>
			<body>Most people don&#39;t actually make a conscious decision to join a trend. They do it without realising.
Many things can affect us, even when we are not aware of them. We all know that sometimes things are hard to resist. And if you don&#39;t know you are being affected by something, how can you resist it?</body>
			</slide>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<name>Making things sticky</name>
		<desc>This course expains how some things become widely popular, while others don&#39;t. This course explores the core concepts of The Tipping Point and factors that make ceratain ideas or behaviours become trends.</desc>
		<count>6</count>	
			<slide>
			<name>How What do you call something that you can&#39;t stop thinking about?</name>
			<body>&#34;Sticky&#34; ideas are ideas that you just can&#39;t stop thinking about, this makes them more likely to become trends.
Memorable products and ideas can be called &#34;sticky&#34;.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do if your customers aren&#39;t paying attention to your product or service?</name>
			<body>If your customers aren&#39;t interested in a product you might be tempted to throw it out and start over.
First though, try making some small changes to it. You can make small changes to the product itself or its advertising or packaging. Sometimes these alterations are enough to get more attention.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Name a children&#39;s TV show that made small changes and gained huge popularity?</name>
			<body>Sesame street became very successful by making just a few small changes. It went from low audience numbers to huge audiences. One change was having real people interact with large puppets. Until then, producers of TV shows believed this would confuse children. But the kids loved it.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>If you really want to capture someone&#39;s attention what should you tell them?</name>
			<body>Things like flashing lights or loud noises will grab people&#39;s attention. However, they won&#39;t keep it. A better way to get and keep someone&#39;s attention is by telling them a story.
People love stories because they&#39;re an entertaining and engaging way to help them understand something.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What element in advertising can be more memorable than words?</name>
			<body>Words are powerful. An ad that describes a product effectively encourages people to buy it. But often an ad needs something more.
Adding an image will often make people pay more attention to an ad. An image is memorable. It sricks in people&#39;s minds even more than words do.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Why do advertisers have to work harder than ever to get people to pay attention?</name>
			<body>Generally, when people watch four TV commercials i a row they don&#39;t remeber any of them. Advvertisements are everywhere&#58; on signs, on the radio, online, etc.
To get consumers to pay attention to a product, advertisers have to create ads that are &#34;sticky&#34; or memorable.</body>
			</slide>
	</chapter>
</course>
</courses>
