<courses>
<course>
<name>Presentation Skills</name>
<id>1</id>
<image>http://api.bibro.ml/academy/images/course_img_presentation.jpg</image>
<count>4</count>
<chapter>
	<name>First things first</name>
	<desc>Know it or not, we use the skill of presentation throughout our life. It&#39;s when we are conscious that we have to prepare a presentation for an audience that we suddenly feel panicked and hide for cover.
This course will teach you the fundamentals of a successful presentation along with important tips and ticks. Whether you have to help others improve their presentation skills, at the end of it all, you&#39;ll be much more confident.</desc>
	<count>8</count>	
		<slide>
		<name>What activity do most people fear?</name>
		<body>Believe it; you are not alone if the thought of public speaking scares you. Many of you might avoid speaking in the public or giving presentations altogether just because you are nervous and afraid to face the public. But there&#39;s a remedy: preparation and perseverance. This topic will help you gather your wits and take the first steps towards a successful presentation.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is the first step in creating a presentation?</name>
		<body>When you need to make a presentation, ask yourself the following questions and write them down. They will help you determine your goal:
&#x2013; What is the purpose of the presentation?
&#x2013; Is it to inform, demonstrate, persuade or just simply entertain?
&#x2013; What do you hope to achieve through this presentation.
&#x2013; What effect will the presentation have on you and the audience?
&#x2013; Defining your objectives will help you focus on preparing your presentation.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is important to do while preparing for a presentation?</name>
		<body>The subject is your topic and your presentation revolves around it. The best subject is something that you are really passionate and knowledgeable about.
For all presentations, research the topic throughly and analyze how it can appeal and stimulate your target audience. Remeber that yiu may have to respnd to your audience&#39;s queries during the Question and Answer session at the end of your presentation. So make sure you know what you are talking about.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What should every presentation do successfully?</name>
		<body>Every successful presentation has a structure that tells a story. Create a story around your presentation that will grab the attention of your audience and get your message delivered. A compelling presentation has a beginning or the &#34;opening&#34;, a middle or the &#34;body&#34; and an end or the &#34;closing&#34;. If you keep that in mind, you will have a clear idea as to what you want to say, when you should say it and how to tie the treads of your presentation together.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is should the opening of a presentation do?</name>
		<body>A good opening line sets the tone for the rest of your presentation. It can be a story, a video, a question, something humorous or even shocking statistic. Think of how this opening will get the attention of the audience.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>When is it your last chance to make an impact?</name>
		<body>The way you close your presentation is your last chance to make an impact on your audience. Reinforce your points, remind the audience about your opening statements and relate them to your ending. For example, if you started with an explosive statement, correlate it with your ending to make a point.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What will make your presentation perfect?</name>
		<body>Even if you do all the preparation in the world, it will not help you on the presentation day until you &#34;practice&#34;. If you memorise, you may sound mechanical, too polished, error-free and unapproachable to the audience. Start practicing at least 15 days before your prresentation and you will sound as if you&#39;re conversing with the audience about a topic that you have mastered.
Practice makes perfect:
&#x2013; Practice out loud in front of a mirror;
&#x2013; Videotape yourself to have a better idea of your body language;
&#x2013; Practice in front of someone else. Ask for their feedback;
&#x2013; Practice first in sections and then when you feel you have mastered each section practice it in it&#39;s entirely;
&#x2013; Once you have practiced it enough times you will feel more comfortable with the material and will be able to come across as more natural in your presentation.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>How do you know if they liked your presentation?</name>
		<body>There are many ways to know what the audience feels at the end of your presentation, primiraly through verbal and non-verbal responses. You can also conduct a survey and find out what the audience liked or disliked in your presentation.</body>
		</slide>
</chapter>
<chapter>
	<name>The Audience</name>
	<desc>Know it or not, we use the skill of presentation throughout our life. It&#39;s when we are conscious that we have to prepare a presentation for an audience that we suddenly feel panicked and hide for cover.
This course will teach you the fundamentals of a successful presentation along with important tips and ticks. Whether you have to help others improve their presentation skills, at the end of it all, you&#39;ll be much more confident.</desc>
	<count>8</count>
		<slide>
		<name>When should you conduct an audience analysis?</name>
		<body>Audience analysis is the first step towards determining your audience and making your presentation based on the information you get.
If you went on a trip with your friends, the way you&#39;d describe the trip to your mother would be different from the way you it to your friends and thenagain, your spouse. That&#39;s why, it is always good to know as much as possible about your audience before you start your session, though we also know that it is doable all the time.
The audience
We generally analyze our audience on three parameters:
1) demographic analysis;
2) attitudal analysis;
3) environmental analysis.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What does demogrraphic analysis help you identify?</name>
		<body>Demographic analysis is the process where you identify your audience based on their age, gender, culture, ethnicity, race, religion and education level. You then adapt your presentation based on the gathered information. Take care that it appeals to all sections of your audience and doesn't offend anyone.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What can you learn from seating arrangements?</name>
		<body>Environmental analysis is about the environment or the venue of the presentation. Find out about the seating arrangement, number of people likely to attend, distraction factors, room lighting etc.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What are two examples of non&#x2013;verbal cues?</name>
		<body>If you look carefully, you can find out if the audience is aying attention to you or drifting off. These are the non&#x2013;verbal cues.
Examples of non&#x2013;verbal audience cues:
1) Facial expressions;
2) Eye contact;
3) How do they mpve their head;
4) Do they respond verbally when you want them to?</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is the first priority when setting up a business?</name>
		<body>No matter how big or small your business, you will have to set aside some time and resources to develop your business idea before you launch it.
The planning and research that you do now will help ensure that your idea is practical, realistic and achievable.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>How can you keep the attention of your audience?</name>
		<body>Use your PowerPoint presentations as visual aids and modes to provide practical and relevant solutions. Keep asking questions to keep them focused on the topic.
The captive audience is a part of your presentation not by choice  but by compulsion. Your session might be a requirement for their promotion, a must do activity for an appraisal, or they are just there to accompany someone. They are the toughest to please.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What do the pragmatists look for in a presentation?</name>
		<body>The pragmatists are partially interested when they arrive for your presentation. They don&#39;t care much about theory and look for the practical utilisation of the topic. Pragmatists are:
&#x2013; always brimming with ideas;
&#x2013; keen to test these ideas in practice;
&#x2013; task-oriented;
&#x2013; are quick to acceot and equally swift to reject anything that doen&#39;t have an obvious application in their work.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What will socially motivated people look for in your presentation?</name>
		<body>The socially motivated audience looks at ways your presentation can affect or better the indiviual&#39;s hold over his&#x2044;her immediate sorroundings. They are individuals striving for achievement and leadership and they will attend your presentation in hope of gaining knowledge towards the same. They also look for ways to improve their social identity and make themselves known among their peers and higher management.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>Why is a committed audience considered the easiest to please?</name>
		<body>The committed section of the audience is the easiest to please. They are mentally prepared to absorb your presentation and take away as much as they can. They generally do not question back, take down notes and have a positive body language. However, just because they are easy to please, you should&#39;t take them for granted. Make eye contact with them, acknowledge them and make them a part of your presentation.</body>
		</slide>
</chapter>
<chapter>
	<name>Presentation Types</name>
	<desc>Know it or not, we use the skill of presentation throughout our life. It&#39;s when we are conscious that we have to prepare a presentation for an audience that we suddenly feel panicked and hide for cover.
This course will teach you the fundamentals of a successful presentation along with important tips and ticks. Whether you have to help others improve their presentation skills, at the end of it all, you&#39;ll be much more confident.</desc>
	<count>5</count>
		<slide>
		<name>What What is the backbone of an informative presentation?</name>
		<body>Informative presentations are the most common types of presentations and are used to provide interesting, unique and useful infrmation to the audience. Follow the steps here to make an informative presentation:
&#x2013; Research your topic thoroughly;
&#x2013; Organize content logically;
&#x2013; Break the content down;
&#x2013; Present.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What is the basis of an analysing presentation?</name>
		<body>The purpose of an analysing presentation is to take alreay existing information and recommend a direction and strategy for the topic.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>How do you conduct instructional presentations?</name>
		<body>The main purpose of an instructional presentation is to instruct or direct your audience for a definitive result. These presentations works well when you&#39;d like your audience to gain new knowledge or a skill. Follow these steps:
&#x2013; Convince your audience about the information with clarity;
&#x2013; Demonstrate the process or skill involved;
&#x2013; Show a connection between the topic and its practical usability;
&#x2013; Make it in interactive session with lots of questions and an open forum for feedback and ideas.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What does a persuasive presentation aim to achieve?</name>
		<body>Persuasive presentations look towards persuading the audience to accept your proposal and work with you. It can, quite often, offer an effective solution to a controversy, dispute or problem. Thkey lies in creating a stable and logical presentation with valid evidence and the right amount of emotional quotient.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>Who What kind of audience memmbers are targeted with inspirational presentations?</name>
		<body>Inspirational presentations make people think and takke note of certain issues and situations. It is important that your presentation appeals to both the emotional and intellectual side of your audience. You want the audience to see the matter through your eyes.</body>
		</slide>			
</chapter>
<chapter>
	<name>PowerPoint</name>
	<desc>Know it or not, we use the skill of presentation throughout our life. It&#39;s when we are conscious that we have to prepare a presentation for an audience that we suddenly feel panicked and hide for cover.
This course will teach you the fundamentals of a successful presentation along with important tips and ticks. Whether you have to help others improve their presentation skills, at the end of it all, you&#39;ll be much more confident.</desc>
	<count>6</count>
		<slide>
		<name>What Why should you create an outline for your presentation?</name>
		<body>Before you delve into creating your slides, start off by first creating an ouutline. An outline will help you organize the key points you want to get across and see how it might flow. It will give you more clarity. This will also save you time as you prepare your presentation.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What should guide an ideal slide layout include?</name>
		<body>Your slide layout determines the attention span of your audience. Consider the following points if you don&#39; want your slides to look busy and distract the audience.
&#x2013; Dont&#39;t use too many words per slide &#x2013; just use keywords or a couple of phrases only;
&#x2013; Use numerical or bullet points instead of complete sentences;
&#x2013;  Jot down a maximum of four to five points per slide for a maximum of one of two minutes;
&#x2013;  Show one point at a time so that the audience remains focused on you and not on the slides;
&#x2013;  Use animation with control and consistency.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>Why is it important to use simple fonts?</name>
		<body>The legibility of your presentation depends on the fonts you choose. Keep the following ponts in mind while creating your presentatio.
&#x2013; Keep your font size to around 18 for general information. Very small fonts are hard for audience to see and very large fonts can intimdate them;
&#x2013; Use different font sizes for your headers, sub&#x2013;headers and general descriptions;
&#x2013; Use a standard font like Times New Roman or Arial fr the slides. Complicated fonts are difficult t read and serve more as a distraction;
&#x2013; Use ALL CAPS only when necessary. If you use it too much or in complete sentences, not only does it become dificcult to read but also makes the audience feel as if they are being shouted at.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What can be annoying and distracting for the audience?</name>
		<body>Like fonts, colour also plays a very important role in maintaining legibility and retain audience attention. Have a look at the following points to ensure a good looking presentation.
&#x2013; Use a font colour that contrasts sharply with background; like a blue/black font on a white background and yellow on a cream background;
&#x2013; Use a standard colour for your main points and sub-points. Don&#39;t use a different colour for every point. It will be serve to distract from the information you are providing.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What type should you have in the background of your presentation?</name>
		<body>Sometimes, the background of your slides can destroy all your hard work. Just follow these simple rules to make it a clear and informative presentation.
&#x2013; Keep your backgrounds attractive but simple;
&#x2013;  You can use also a solid colour that contrast with the text or use images to fill the background. Just make sure that the text is readable;
&#x2013; Always have a consistent background. Be informative, not disruptive.</body>
		</slide>
		<slide>
		<name>What How do you ensure your slides have correct spelling and grammar?</name>
		<body>Be aware! Your presentation will reflect badly on you if you use incorrect spelling and grammar. Always proof-read your slides multiple times before your presentation. Check for spelling mistakes, use of repetitive words and any grammatical errors. If you are not a native user of the language you are presenting in, have someone else with the language proficiency check your presentation.</body>
		</slide>			
</chapter>
</course>
<course>
<name>Job Interview Tips</name>
<id>2</id>
<image>http://api.bibro.ml/academy/images/course_img_job_interview.jpg</image>
	<count>4</count>
	<chapter>
		<name>Expectations</name>
		<desc>The interview is your chance to showcase your winning attributes and learn if this job opportunity is right for you. This course willl teach you everything you need to learn to make the most out of the interview process.</desc>
		<count>5</count>	
			<slide>
			<name>What do most people feel in an interview?</name>
			<body>Sometimes just understanding what you can expect from the interview process will help alleviate any anxiety you might have about it
It will also motivate you to take full advantage of this opportunity and not feel intimidated. Remember that you are being sees as meeting basic qualifications for the job, otherwise they would not want to learn more about you.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is the goal of any interviewer?</name>
			<body>The interviewer is hoping you will be the winning candidate for the position because that will make his or her own job easier. They will not have to continue their search.
While some of their questions might feel like they are trying to trap or trick you, they ar actually all designed to simply learn more about you and determine if you are the right fit for te job. On the other hand, always remember that the interviewer is not your new friend.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Why What should you do when you are asked about yourself?</name>
			<body>You can expect to be asked to tell the interviewer about yourself and elaborate on highlights from your previous work experience or other activities. Some call this &#34;selling yourself&#34; or &#34;pitching yourself&#34;. This is a key component of the interview that you can prepare for and control. While it might be a general question, you have a great opportunity to be specific. By providing pre-selected examples of your previous success stories, you can emphasise the challenges you have faced, the actions you have taken to overcome them and the impressive results you secured.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do when asked about your weaknesses?</name>
			<body>You can also expect the unexpected! The interviewer might have questions that don&#39;t continue focus on your strenghts but rather your weaknesses. You will need to e prepared to answer how you have overcome challenges witth concrete, positive examples.
Describe a time when you were unale to meet the expectations of management. What did you do about it? Answer: I was asked to come up with an outreach plan to gain more business from the local community. My plan was well over the budget and not approved. I did some research and gave some examples of their initiatives that had been successful in generating higher profits for other businesses. My manager appreciated my inititive and understood the value of my plan in a new light. If was approved and eventually saw great success in terms of our own increased profits.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Why should you ask your own questions about the job?</name>
			<body>You will be expected to have some questins about the job and the company. This is an important component of the interview and &#x2013; contrary to what you might think &#x2013; having questionsis better than not having ny. It will give you a chance to show you have paid attention during the interview as well as expand on your own research and interest in the opportunity.</body>
			</slide>			
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<name>Pre&#x2013;interview</name>
		<desc>The interview is your chance to showcase your winning attributes and learn if this job opportunity is right for you. This course willl teach you everything you need to learn to make the most out of the interview process.</desc>
		<count>9</count>
			<slide>
			<name>How is knowing who will interview you helpful?</name>
			<body>Confirm who will be interviewing you and their role and position in the hiring process. There may be more than one person interviewing you. You will need to address your answers to everyone in the rom, yet if you know who is there, you can favour certain people with certain answers based on their role.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you bring to every interview?</name>
			<body>You will need to have attractive hard copies of your updated resume and other supporting documentation ready to distribute in the interview, even if you sent them in advance electronically. If you can provide work samples that further shocase your credentials, now is the time to make sure they are in great shape and ready to be presented within the interview. If you are presenting anything on a digital device or computer, make sure all technical issues are in order for the interview.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>Who will make the best reference?</name>
			<body>You need to also be prepared to provide references if asked to do so. Take time before the interview to consider who would be the best professional references to recommend you for this particular job. Who will be impressive to the interviewer? Who can speak highly of you in a professional setting and give examples of your strenghts?</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do when contacting professional references?</name>
			<body>Plan time to contact your references &#x2013; new and old. Brief them on the job you are interviewing for and secure their support and contact information. Let them know the name of the person who may be contacting them in the near future.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is the important to do before phone or Skype interviews?</name>
			<body>If you are having a phone interview, remember to find out if there is a dial in number and password beforehand. If you are having a Skype interview, make sure you ave activated your account and the interviewer knows the technical information required to reach you at the designated interview time.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What does comparing your skills with the job requirements allow you to do?</name>
			<body>Your goal is to compare what you have to offer with the job requirements and the company&#39;s goals. If there are ares you are lacking in experince, you can prepare how to handle those potential concerns in the interview. Best of all, you will be able to assess which of your skills do match the job requirements. Focus on how you will make the most out of these advantages.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How can you ask fr help to learn more about the job?</name>
			<body>You can research the job in various ways.
To start, ask the company itself or the recruiting team to direct you to more information abou the job and the companyYou want to thoroughly understand the company, what they do, what they produce and&#x2044;or what services they offer and to whom.
If the information they offer is limited, use the Internet, your own network of contacts and the library to gather more information. Sounding like an &#34;insider&#34; will encourage the interviewer to see you already in the job.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is important to have completed before any interview?</name>
			<body>Research the company&#39;s competition and the industry you would be working in.
Try to uncover the challenges the compeny has faced as well as their accomplishments. With this knowledge, you can evaluate which of your skill sets can help them achieve their overall goals. What is their competition doing that you can do even better.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is one advantages of knowing as much as you can about the company you are applying to?</name>
			<body>Any knowledge you have about the company, its team and their industry will help you shine in your interviiew.</body>
			</slide>				
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<name>Your Sakes Pitch</name>
		<desc>The interview is your chance to showcase your winning attributes and learn if this job opportunity is right for you. This course willl teach you everything you need to learn to make the most out of the interview process.</desc>
		<count>5</count>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you focus on communicating during an inteerview?</name>
			<body>One of the most important things you can do to prepare for the interview is t review your work experiences and do an analysis that helps you understand and communicate what your strongest attributes are.
You need to identify and write down what your duties and responsibilities were in previous jobs and what actions you had to take accomplish them. You need to understand what key attributes you employed to get results.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How Why is it important to tell success stories about your prebious work experiences?</name>
			<body>From your previous work experineces, choose at least three examples of what you would consider success stories.
Try to find examples that demonstrate attributes and results that meet key qualificatins for the positionyou ar interviewing for. It helps to choose success stories that started with problems that might be similar to the ones you would face in your new position.
Telling those stories will become the spine of your sales pitch in the interview. When asked to give a review of your career and your accomplishments you will bbe ready to emphasise these highlights. This should take between five to seven minutes.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is the best way to organise the structure of your success stories?</name>
			<body>A success story needs a beggining, middle and end. Structure the telling of your success story in the folowing order:
&#x2013; Identify the challenge you faced and what you assessed to be the main problem;
&#x2013; Describe the action you took to respond to the problem and resolve it;
&#x2013; Describe the results you achieved;
&#x2013; To remember these three steps think AAR &#x2013; Assessment&#x2044;Action&#2044;Results.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How What is the best way to handle weak spots in your resume?</name>
			<body>We all have weaknesses. You cannot possibly go into an interview fulfilling every qualification. What you can do is be realistic about where you are lacking and think about additional ways you can contribute your unique attributes to the job.
You probably have more to offer the job than you think. Consider areas in the new job in which you might not have direct work experience. Think of examples from other areas of your life that equally demonstrate your competencies.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should you do before the end of the interview?</name>
			<body>Most interviewers will conclude by asking if you have any questions. You should always say yes. Your questions, prepared in advance, are another aspect of the interview that you can control. They can serve several purposes.</body>
			</slide>			
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<name>Interview Questions</name>
		<desc>The interview is your chance to showcase your winning attributes and learn if this job opportunity is right for you. This course willl teach you everything you need to learn to make the most out of the interview process.</desc>
		<count>5</count>
			<slide>
			<name>How What can you do to help you handle any interview questions?</name>
			<body>Many people think the hardest part of an interview is when the interviewer asks questions.
Because you do not know the questions in advance, this requires yyou to think on your feet. What if you make a mistake or give the wrong impression? Worse &#x213; what if you do not have an answer? Don&#39;t worry. If you understand what the interviewer is really trying to learn, you can handle anything that comes at you.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What should is one skill that interviewers are trying to assess?</name>
			<body>Interviewers are often trying to discover how you will perform with different responsibilities &#2013; as an individual and as a manager&#2044;leader.
Along with wanting to know what motivates you, interviewers want to assess your various skill in the following areas:
&#2013; People skills;
&#2013; Analytical skills;
&#2013; Problem&#2013;solving skills;
&#2013; Leadership skills.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How can you ensure that you use opportunities to sell yourself?</name>
			<body>Come into the interview with a mental list of examples from previous work experiences that display your strengths in a range of categories.
When the interviewer asks you a question, listen carefully to determine which skill or strength they are to reveal in you. Providing a verbal example f a situation in which you demonstrated those qualities will give you the tools to craft effective answer.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>What is one key thing that all questions are trying to discover?</name>
			<body>Questions like &#34;Tell me about a time when you disagreed with your boss. What did you do about it&#34; are tricky. You don't want to be negative about your boss or come across as being difficult to work with.
Be honest, bu do not leave a bad impression. For example, you may simply want a new job so you can make more money. If this is the case, you need to think through how to show your enthusiasm for the job itself, while articulating your desire to achieve higher compensation for your skills and experience.</body>
			</slide>
			<slide>
			<name>How do you discuss a weakness at the interview?</name>
			<body>Be prepared for a question that will ask you to describe any weaknesses you have.
To prepare fo this, think of weakness you could discuss that you could put a positive spin on. Make sure you pick a weakness that will not be an issue for the job you are applying for.</body>
			</slide>			
	</chapter>
</course>
</courses>
